Abraham is a adventure, drama, tv movie film directed by Joseph Sargent.
Rather than choosing a great leader or king, God chooses Abraham, an elderly shepherd
from Mesopotamia, as the way to establish his Covenant with mankind...
A man of great faith, Abraham continues to believe in God
even when He seems to have abandoned him.
Abraham, played by Richard Harris.
Sara, played by Barbara Hershey.
Hagar, played by Carolina Rosi.
Terach, played by Vittorio Gassman.
Lot, played by Andrea Prodan.
Eliezer, played by Gottfried John.
Abraham is a 1993 television miniseries based on the life of the
Biblical patriarch Abraham produced by Five Mile River Films.
It was shot in Ouarzazate, Morocco.
Directed by Joseph Sargent, it stars Richard Harris as Abraham, Barbara Hershey as
Sarah, Maximilian Schell as Pharaoh and Vittorio Gassman as Terah.
The film is the first in the Bible Collection series by TNT.
The film explores themes of bible, biography,
catholic, religious film, christian film.
The tone is emotional.